<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Apache ESME</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section id="news">
      <title>News</title>
      <p> <strong> December 2008 </strong> </p>
          
      <p> ESME  has just joined the Apache Incubator</p>      
    </section>
    <section id="overview">
      <title>Overview</title>
      <p>
       Enterprise Social Messaging Experiment (ESME) is a secure and highly scalable microsharing and micromessaging platform that allows people to discover and meet one another and get controlled access to other sources of information, all in a business process context.
       </p> 
         <p>
       The ESME server is written in Scala and uses the Lift web framework to
produce a browser-based user interface and also to expose a REST API.
The ESME architecture has been devised to meet the business
requirements associated with reliability and scalability. The use of
the Scala programming language and the Lift web framework on the
server provides rapid development capability as well as browser push
functionality ("Comet") as standard. The open server side architecture
allows other messaging environments - internal (Alerts, Enterprise
Services, etc.) as well as public (Twitter, external web-services,
etc.) - to be consumed as messaging sources. An event-driven actions
framework within ESME allows users to filter their information flow as
well as to forward ESME messages to other systems via HTTP or email.
    </p>
     </section>
     <section id="history">
	     <title> History </title>
	     <p> If you look at the origins of the ESME project, you will find that the origin was in a plurk (a micro-blogging site like twitter) conversation that at some point moved to the SAP SDN wiki. The project then moved to Assembla and then Google Code</p>
	     <p>The team involved was originally primarily made of individuals associated with the SAP community but has since expanded to include others from outside that community. The global team includes members from a variety of different nations ranging from India, Spain, Norway, Rumania, UK, etc.</p>
      </section>
     <section id="features">
	     <title> Features </title>
	     <p>Present Features</p>
	     <ul>
		     <li>Adobe Air client</li>
		     <li>Web client</li>
		     <li>Extensive set of built-in actions</li>
		     <li>Login via Open-ID</li>					     
	     </ul>
	     <p>Planned Features</p>
	     <ul>
		     <li>Federation scenarios</li>
		     <li>Groups</li>		     
	     </ul>
	     <p>A few requested Features</p>
	     <ul>
		     <li>ERP notifictions</li>
		     <li>Prioritization</li>
		     <li>Show local time for users</li>
	     </ul>
      </section>	    
  </body>
</document>
